now going back to our many core
challenges we have seen that the number
of cores as it grows makes the coherence
traffic grow and we looked at solutions
to deal with that we then looked at the
problem of the off-chip traffic also
growing with the number of course and we
just saw that a large shared but
distributed last level cache can help
with this problem the next problem we
face is that the coherence directory
that we need is just way too large to
fit on chip because we have a scalable
onship network and no longer a bus we
need directory coherence but a
traditional directory has one entry for
each possible memory block the memory
can be many gigabytes in size that might
require even billions of directory
entries and that won't fit on ship so
how do we deal with that problem